africanentrepreneurshipaward.com 2018-11-23

# Privacy Policy - African Entrepreneurship Award - African Entrepreneurship Award

#### **1\. General principles**

The African Entrepreneurship Award (AEA) is aware of your legitimate concerns about privacy and is fully committed to maintaining the integrity, confidentiality, security, and accuracy of your Personal Information in accordance with applicable privacy legislation and best industry practices.

The Online Privacy Policy (the “Policy“) helps you understand the guiding principles applied by the AEA to the collection, use, disclosure, retention, and disposal of and access to Personal Information on this site.

Because privacy concerns and legal and business requirements evolve continually, the AEA may have to change its Policy at any time without advance notice and therefore you are invited to review it regularly. Access to and use of this site are also governed by the AEA site Terms and Conditions that you should review.

By using the the AEA website and providing us with your Personal Information, you agree that the AEA use the latter in accordance with privacy laws and this Policy. For purposes of this Policy, “Personal Information” refers to any information about an identifiable individual and/or the “Business Proposal” information recorded on the AEA site.

#### **2\. Guiding principles**

Our Policy rests on the following seven guiding principles:

##### **2.1 Identifying the purposes of use**

The nature and scope of the Personal Information we need depends to a great extent on which products, solutions or services are of interest to you. The AEA will collect Personal Information only in relation to its operating programs in order to:

_Identify you_

Personal Information such as your name, telephone number, personal address, date of birth, gender, citizenship, identification information and password helps us to identify you.

_Provide ongoing services_

Personal Information about you and your business allows us to communicate with you and respond adequately and promptly to your enquiries about applications, accounts, or other online services.

_Recognize your achievements_

The AEA is held annually across Africa in recognition of social entrepreneurship. To select and contact the winners for this prestigious award, the judges require certain Personal Information concerning, for instance, your business plans and your community involvement.

_Protect you and us against errors and fraud_

All your activities are electronically logged, so that the AEA can review them in case of any suspicious activity. The AEA uses software to monitor site traffic and to detect unauthorized attempts to upload, change information, or otherwise cause damage.

_Promote our products, solutions and services to you_

When you specify your consent on any online AEA subscription or registration form, the AEA may, from time to time, use your email or regular mailing address to send you information on the AEA, the mentorship program, solutions and services, trends, business opportunities, or other topics and events of current interest. In order to do so, the AEA may also collect the information that you provided on the subscription or registration form, such as your name, address, telephone number(s), and your language of preference.

##### **2.2 Obtaining your Consent**

Your Consent can be express or implied (“Consent”). It can be expressed in writing, or electronically. Your Consent can be implied through your action or inaction. For instance, when you file an application, we conclude that you have consented to the collection, use, and disclosure of the Personal Information it contains for the intended purposes. The same conclusion may be drawn when you use one of our products, solutions or services. Your Consent can also be given by your authorized representative, for instance, if he/she is providing Personal Information and is competing to win the AEA. Your Personal Information will be viewed by the AEA employees or representatives for the purposes of their work or for which it was given, as outlined in section 2.1.

In some circumstances, the AEA may collect, use, or disclose Personal Information without your Consent for legal, security, or processing reasons, or when it is impossible to obtain your Consent in cases contemplated by applicable privacy legislation. Examples of such circumstances include compliance with applicable laws or court orders, the protection of the public interest, the AEA’s rights, fraud detection and prevention, the use of Personal Information emanating from a third party, and the collection of overdue accounts.

You can withdraw your Consent at any time, provided AEA is given reasonable notice and there are no legal or contractual requirements preventing this.

##### **2.3 Limiting collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information**

The AEA will not, without your Consent, collect, use, or disclose Personal Information except for the purposes identified or for a use consistent with those purposes or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law. With your Consent, the AEA may obtain Personal Information from third parties.

The AEA may transfer (or otherwise make available) Personal Information to third parties who provide services on our behalf. For example, we may use service providers to process Personal Information, authorize and process payments, or host our website. Personal Information may be stored and processed outside of the African continent, including the United States and the United Kingdom, by our third-party service providers. Our service providers are not authorized to use or disclose your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf or as otherwise required by applicable law.

The AEA is subject to various legal and business requirements in dealing with document retention, including electronic documents such as emails. The AEA will retain the Personal Information only for such periods of time as may be prescribed by applicable laws and regulations, as deemed necessary for the identified purposes. In accordance with legal requirements and applicable guidelines, the AEA will destroy, erase, render anonymous, or otherwise dispose of Personal Information after such period of time.

##### **2.4 Providing access and accuracy**

Subject to legal requirements provided by the applicable laws of the AEA host country, the AEA will respect your right of access to your Personal Information by informing you of its procedures and requirements for responding to your request for access. The AEA will act diligently to give you access, at minimal or no cost wherever possible. In certain exceptional circumstances, the AEA may not be able to give you access to your Personal Information. For example, information that may contain references to other persons or to the AEA’s proprietary information, or be covered by solicitor-client privilege.

You can challenge the accuracy of your Personal Information and request corrections if you believe there are errors or omissions. You may also require in certain circumstances that an annotation be attached to your Personal Information reflecting any correction requested but not made, or that such annotation or correction be notified to certain individuals.

The AEA will take all reasonable steps to ensure Personal Information used on an ongoing basis is as accurate, up-to-date, and complete for the purposes in which it was collected; the AEA will rely on you to inform it of any required corrections.

##### **2.5 Responding to your privacy concerns**

The AEA will respond to your questions and investigate diligently any complaints with respect to your Personal Information.

##### **2.6 Complying with applicable privacy legislation**

Your and the AEA’s rights and obligations regarding privacy are governed by applicable privacy legislation. The application and interpretation of this Policy and of our guiding privacy principles are subject to and will comply with such legislation.

#### **3\. Use of cookies**

A cookie is a small text file containing certain pieces of information that a website server creates and puts on your computer. The AEA uses persistent cookies to enable us to better serve you when you visit our site.

Persistent cookies are written or stored on your hard drive until the expiry date. The AEA’s persistent cookies are used, for example, to retain information that you provided so that the AEA website can be personalized accordingly, or to determine if a certain user has previously completed one of our surveys, so that he/she will not be surveyed again.

The cookies used by the AEA are designed so they do not reveal any Personal Information on their own.

By accessing our site, you consent to the use of cookies and agree to have your browser set to accept cookies. If you want to access our site but don’t agree to receive cookies, you can do so by modifying the preferences of your browser. However, note that by not accepting cookies, you may not be able to use all the features of our site.

#### **4\. Third-party social media**

The use of social media by the AEA is an extension of its Web presence. Social media accounts are public and not hosted on the AEA servers. Users who decide to interact with the AEA through these media must read the conditions of service and privacy policies of these third-party providers of services and applications used in order to access them.

#### **5\. Web analytics**

##### **5.1 Analytics**

Web analytics involves the collection, analysis, measurement and presentation of data on website traffic and on visits, for the purpose of understanding and optimizing Web use. The information collected by the cookies may be used by Web analytics to keep your interactions with the AEA in memory.

Information used for the purpose of web analytics is collected pursuant to the applicable laws mentioned above. The AEA uses the information for its own internal statistical and analytical purposes, to evaluate and enhance users’ experience of the website by identifying customer preferences and trends that we may use for marketing purposes and to further develop our business and operations.

When your computer requests an AEA Web page, the AEA collects the following types of information, for web analytics, such as:

**–** The Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer;

**–** The date and time of your request;

**–** The pages viewed and downloaded;

**–** The identifier attributed to registered users accessing restricted areas on the site;

**–** The type of operating system; and

**–** The type of browser & browser settings used.

Data collected for web analytics purposes will sometimes go outside of Africa and may be subject to the governing legislation of any such country.

##### **5.2 Security**

The AEA uses software to monitor site traffic and to detect unauthorized attempts to upload, change information, or otherwise cause damage. The software receives and records the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of the computers that have visited this site, including the date and time of visits, the pages that were viewed and downloaded, and the identifier attributed to any registered user who accesses restricted areas on this site. The software also captures information regarding the type of browser and operating system. The AEA does not attempt to link the IP addresses and the identifiers with the identity of users visiting this site unless there is an attempt to damage the site.

#### **6\. Responding to your concerns**

For questions or comments regarding this Policy, for additional information about the management of Personal Information at the AEA, or to consult or modify your Personal Information, contact us by email, phone, or mail.

To file a privacy complaint concerning the collection, use, disclosure, retention, and disposal of or access to Personal Information, please contact info@african-award.com
